



# Kalaipriya Kannan

Lead SME L&D Data and Reporting | Business Analyst



+91-9840511730





kalaipriya.kannan@gmail.com

Certified Scrum Master and Seasoned Business Analyst offering 9 years of industry success. Expert on business and systems requirements, user acceptance testing and end-user training. Diligent worker with strong communication and task prioritization skills. Worked on diversified portfolio such as Life Sciences, Healthcare, Blockchain Frameworks and L&D Data Reporting. Strong experience in Business Analysis and Data Analysis, proficient in SQL, Tableau.



#### **Skills**

Business Need Analysis

Project & Team Management

Project & Team Management

Very Good

Requirement Analysis

Excellent

Data Analysis & Reporting

Very Good

Business Consulting & Advisory

Excellent

Strategic planning

Very Good

Agile Methodologies

Good



## **Work History**

## Senior Business Analyst

Carelon Global Solutions, Bangalore

- Acting as lead point of contact for L&D Data and Reporting
- Working in parallel projects (L&D active and Blockchain frameworks shadowing) assisting the leadership in decision making for application deployments
- Created dashboards to monitor and track key performance indicators.
   Generated business intelligence reports to inform strategic decision-making.

2021-04 - Current

2017-05 - 2021-03

- Working with development team to understand technical needs and managed sprint cycle
- Developed business solutions leveraging existing technology to meet requirements of key stakeholders, product leadership teams, and steering committees
- Reporting monthly data analysis findings to leadership to use in making organizational L&D decisions
- Analyzed key aspects of business to evaluate factors driving results and summarized into presentations.
- Improved business direction by prioritizing customers and implementing changes based on collected feedback.
- Conducted interviews with key business users to collect information on business processes and user requirements.
- Generated ad-hoc reports to evaluate specific business requirements.
- Supported leadership team with reporting, analysis, and business presentations to inform divisional strategies.
- Lead end-to-end release and implementation life cycles of product enhancements by ensuring project requirements are met with optimal business results

## Business Lead & Subject Matter Expert of L&D

Deloitte USI, Hyderabad

- With strong experience in areas of change and release management, defect analysis, system configuration, stakeholder communication and providing training related to new learning solutions
- Managed team of 6 and acted as escalation point of contact for various learning leads across EMEA and APAC region, directly interact with vendor for any change requests or enhancement requests basis the need
- Collaborated with Project Owners, Project Managers to provide functional release per sprint cycle
- Assisted management with backlog refinement sessions
- Identified and implemented operational improvements, enhancements, customizations and rolling out learning solutions that arise from the need analysis, communications & project management
- Facilitated various user groups meeting with learning leaders across member firms in different geographical regions for best practices and gaining consensus visioning to business growth
- Evaluated staff performance and provide coaching to address inefficiencies. Evaluated customer needs and feedback to drive product and service improvements.
- Created and managed project plans, timelines, and budgets.

## Programmer Analyst

Cognizant Technology Solutions, Chennai

- Worked on L&D requirements and delivered to meet client needs for functionality and organization development.
- Performed regression and system-level testing to verify software quality prior to release.
- Developed need based training modules for developing multi skilled work force and mentored new team members to come up learning curve
- Managed the team of 12 for a large pharmaceutical client in the UK with focus on excelling business targets & service delivery metrics
- Monitored and evaluated metrics, prepared reports on standards & performance target
- Ensured quality services are provided and document functionalities are maintained



#### Education

Education

Vel Tech Institutions - Chennai

**B.Tech: Information Technology** 



## **Certifications**

- Professional Scrum Master (PSM1)
- Certified Blockchain Expert (CBE)
- Certified Blockchain Developer (CBD)
- IBM Blockchain Essentials
- IBM Certified Big Data and Data Science Foundations
- Scrum Concepts & Product Owner
- Agile Principles & Methodologies



## **Technical Skills**

SQL

Tableau

Python

Advanced Excel

HTML

Postman

2010-08 - 2014-04



# **Tools Worked**



Jupiter Notebook

ServiceNow

Salesforce

Remedy

MS SQL Server

Oracle DB



## **LMS Worked**



SuccessFactors

Saba Cloud

Workday

Corner Stone on Demand (CSOD)

Oracle LMS

Plateau



# **Blockchain Frameworks**



Hyperledger Fabric

Ethereum

(Permissioned & Private networks)